Guide to the Kelly Marie Martin Riot Grrrl Collection 1977-2001 (Bulk 1992-1998) MSS.349
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kelly Marie Martin Riot Grrrl Collection
1977-2001
1992-1998
Fales Library and Special Collections
Martin, Kelly
MSS.349
4 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript cases and 1 oversize box
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Content
This collection contains zines, magazines, and flyers collected by Kelly Marie Martin in the early and mid-1990s. It also contains copies and original masters of Martin's own zine, Thorn.
Arrangement
This collection is separated into two series:
Missing Title
Series I: Zines, Magazines, and Flyers
Series II: Thorn
Both series are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
Kelly Marie Martin is an interdisciplinary artist, musician and activist living in Los Angeles. She plays guitar in the Old Time trio Triple Chicken Foot, with Ben Guzmán on fiddle/mandolin and Mike Heinle on banjo, and is a founding board member and "Cook" at the Bicycle Kitchen, a not-forprofit bicycle repair and education workshop in central Los Angeles.
Martin co-founded the zine Thorn with friend Tammy Rae Carland in San Francisco in 1992, and continued to produce 5 more issues of the zine on her own under the editrix moniker of Keroscene. In 1993, Thorn was "Zine of the Month" in Sassy magazine, and was banned in Canada when it was sent along with the zine Hippie Dick to the Spew conference in Toronto.
Martin has an MFA from the University of California, Irvine, and has exhibited her work in Los Angeles, Philadelphia, and Rejmyre, Sweden and performed at REDCAT and Highways. Her work has been published in The Journal of Aesthetics and Protest, Imaginary Syllabi (Palm Press, 2011), and Cog Magazine as well as in numerous self-published books and zines. In 2009, Martin published a book of her 4x5 photographs called Bike It: Portraits of My Bicipandilla.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Originals for Thorn zine are currently not available to researchers due to preservation concerns.
Feminism; Queer theory.; Zines; Punk culture.; Riot grrrl movement.; Activism (LGBTQ); Martin, Kelly; Carland, Tammy Rae, 1965-
- Series I: Zines, Magazines, and Flyers
  - 2 [cents], #4, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 9 to 5: Profile of Working Women, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ache, #2, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - All Liquored Up..., Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anarcho-Homocore Nite Club, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - And Everything Nice, #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Angst Comics Grab Bag, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bamboo Girl, #1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bananafish, #10, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BB Gun, #1, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beehive, #1-4, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ben is Dead, #19, 24, 1992, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beyond the Blackout, #4, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bikini Kill flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bilge, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - A Bit Chewy, #1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blue Persuasion, #4, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Boo Boo, #1, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brat Attack, #4, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Broken Spoke, #2, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bruce on a Stick, #4, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bust, #1, 5, 8, 1993, 1995, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Camp Runamok!, #2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Catbox Room, #3, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Certain Comfort, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Certifiable, #3, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chica Loca, #1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chickfactor, #3, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chop Suey Spex, #1, 2, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cool Beans, #8 (with CD), 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - A Couple of Things for a Whiteboy to Think About - flyer, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Courtney Love - AOL postings, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Crotch Potato, #1, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cupsize, #3, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Defixiones, Will and Testament, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Diaspora, #1, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Disaster While You Wait, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Diseased Pariah News, #8, 10, 1993, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dishwasher, #13, 14, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Doris, #1, 2, 3, 1994, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Double Bill, #1, 2, 1991, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Drastic Lives, #1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Engine of Lies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Epicenter Women's Outreach Koalition (EWOK) presents: Women's Outreach Weekend '93, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Factsheet 5, #46, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Feeding the Fowls, #17, 18, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Felicity, #1, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Fembot, 5 issues (not numbered), Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Femme Flicke, #3, 4, 7, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - First, #1, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Flesh and Bones, #7, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Free to Fight!, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Frighten the Horses, #7, 11, 13, 1991, 1993, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fuel Kicker, #5, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fuh Cole, #2, 3, 4, 1993, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fussy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Future Safe: Estate Planning for Artists in a Time of AIDS, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fuzz, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - /Gæ•räj/, issues @, ß, 1993, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Giant Robot, #2, 11, 1995, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Girl Germs, #3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Girl Hero, #1, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Girl Jock, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Global Mail, #7, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Gobnascale: House of the Storyteller, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Grunge, #4, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Guide for Sensible Sex - flyer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gurls with Guns, #7, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hearts can Starve, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hippie Dick!, #1, 5, 6, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Holy Titclamps, #12, 13, 14, 15, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Honey Kids, #1, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Horse (Dead Air), #6, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Horse Fever, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hothead Paisan, #2, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hubba, #1, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - I Hate Brenda, the Newsletter, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - I [heart] Amy Carter, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Idol Worship, #2, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Imaginary Grace, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Junk - flyer, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Kittums, #3, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ladyfest, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Liar, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Libel, #1, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Low, #16, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Mea Culpa, #1, 2, 3, 4, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Metamorphosis, #1, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Milky, #2, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Mmm..., #4, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Monozine, #4, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Monstar, #9, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - A Month in Space, #1, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Moonshine, #14, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Mother, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Moxie, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mrs. Juicy-O, #2, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Mudflap, 3 issues, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - My Girlfriend's Shrink, #6, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - My Jodie Book, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - My Last Nerve, #2, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - My Zine, #1, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Nerdy Grrrl Revolution, #1, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - New Order, #2, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - No Justice, React! - flyer, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The NYCS Weekly Breeder, vol. 5, #1, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Odyssey, #2, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Oi Boy, #2, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Olly-Up, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - On Our Rag, #4, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Out of WAC, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - P is for Pretty, #1, 3, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Paintspot, #3, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Papercut, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Peep, #1, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Pladclown, #4, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Plotz, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Plunger, #3, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Poems for Superheroes, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Polvo Fiction, #1, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Prayers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Princess, #1, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Psycho.Moto, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Publicsfear, #3, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Push, #8, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Pussy Boy, #2, Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Queenie, #1, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Queer Intercourse, #6, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Random Letters to Ransom Girls, Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Riot Gear, #3, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Road Cone, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rock for Choice - flyer, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rockr Grl Retrospective, #20, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rollerderby, #18, 22, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Room 112, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Rump, #11-15, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ruth, #1, 3, 1993, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Sad Magazine, #4, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Scratch, #1, 2, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Self Esteem Queen, #1, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - She's a Moving Weapon, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Shit Happy, #3, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Siren, #2, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Snak Fud, #8, 9, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Snarla, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sooprize Package, #1, Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Soup, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Southern Hysteria, #1, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Spare Rib Magazine, #228, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Sparkly Kitty Stickers, #3, Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Spazz, #13, 14, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Spunk, #2.4, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Starfucker, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - SWIM: Demonstrate at the Grammys - flyer, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - SWIM Notes, #2, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Take Back Your Life, Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Teen Mom, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Thee Kali Circle, #2, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Thing, #7, 8, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Thrift Score, #9, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Time's Up, #6, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tommy!, #4, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Twisted, #2, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Unauthorized Biography of Timo Ellis, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Verge, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Violet, #1, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - War News, #10, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - WHAM! - sticker, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - What Little Boys are Made of..., Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Whorezine, #11, 14, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Why Bother?, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Without - story / program, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Word, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Y is for Yuck, #1, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Yer Not the Boss of Me!, #4, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Zine Guide, #1, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Zinehorn, Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Series II: Thorn
  Conditions Governing Access
  Originals for Thorn zine are currently not available to researchers due to preservation concerns.
  - Thorn, #1, Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Thorn, #2, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Thorn, #3, Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Thorn, #4, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Thorn, #5, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Thorn, #6, Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Oversize Series I: Zines, Magazines, and Flyers
  - Afterimage, v.18, #3, 4; v.20, #4, 1990, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Obscuritant, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Zero Hour, #3, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Oversize Series II: Thorn
  - Thorn original master, #1, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Thorn original master, #2, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Thorn original master, #3, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Thorn original master, #4, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Thorn original master, #5, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Thorn original master, #6, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)